rsmuk.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy and cookies | RSM UK

### Privacy and cookies statement 

This page contains the information gathering and use policies adopted by RSM UK Group LLP (“RSM UK”) in connection with this web site (the “Site”) and any marketing campaigns, including by email (the “Emails”). These policies are subject to periodic review and any changes will be included within this section of the site.

RSM UK is not responsible for the privacy policies of third party web sites to which any links are provided. You should check the privacy policies on these sites before providing any personal information.

### Cookies

About the cookies we use, why we use them, and their impact upon you.

A cookie is a small file, typically of letters and numbers, which may be placed on your computer when you access a website.  Cookies generally allow the website to recognise your computer and browsing activity if you return to the website.

We use both persistent cookies and session cookies as further detailed below.  Persistent cookies allow our website to recognise you when you return to our site another time. This provides us with useful analytics that help us optimise our website and your visits.  Session cookies exist just for the life of your current visit whilst you have your browser open.  They are not stored on your hard disk and are erased when you exit your web browser.

If you would like more information on cookies, we recommend the [direct.gov.uk internet browser cookies page](https://www.gov.uk/support/cookies).

### Cookies we use

**Marketo Analytics**

This site uses a Marketo tracking cookie, _mkto_trk, which allows us to collect information about how you use our site. Unless you have accessed web content via a marketing email  from us your visits will be tracked anonymously.

However if you have accessed such web content  we can use your visitor data to provide custom content related to your specific interests. By using this website you are consenting to the above use of your data. If you wish to block this cookie, see below for more information about manually managing cookies.

**Sitecore Analytics**

We use this type of cookie to understand how our website is being used and in order to deliver content via widgets that we think will be especially relevant to you.

Session cookie:  SC_ANALYTICS_SESSION_COOKIE

Persistent cookie:  SC_ANALYTICS_GLOBAL_COOKIE

**Google Analytics**

We use this type of cookie to understand how our website is being used in order to improve the user experience. User data is all anonymous.

Persistent cookie: _utma/b/z

Session cookie: ASP.NET_SessionId, _utmc

**Social buttons**

On many of the pages of our website you will see ‘social buttons’.  These allow you to share or bookmark pages on our site. 

Social media sites such as Twitter, Google, Facebook, and LinkedIn may collect information about your internet activity, including if your visit to our site and the specific pages you are on if you are logged into their services, even if you don’t click on the button.

You should check the privacy and cookies policies of each of these sites to see how exactly they use your information and to find out how to opt out, or delete, such information.

Further information

  1. [Facebook cookies ](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)
  2. [Twitter cookies ](https://twitter.com/privacy)
  3. [Google cookies ](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/)
  4. [LinkedIn cookies   
](http://www.linkedin.com/static?key=privacy_policy)

### Manually managing cookies

There are a number of ways you can manually manage cookies on your computer/device. Read more on the [About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/legal-notices/cookies/).

If you access the Internet from more than one computer/device it is important to ensure each browser is configured to suit your cookie preferences.

If you wish to block all cookies all the time you can set your browser to do this.  It is important to note that blocking cookies may result in some parts of our site not working properly. This may affect your browsing experience.

**Collection of information**

As a visitor, you do not have to submit any personal information in order to use the Website. The Site collects only personally identifiable information that is specifically and voluntarily provided by visitors. Such information may consist of, but is not limited to, your name, current job title, company address, email address and telephone and fax numbers. This can be in order to:

  * Request specific materials or information by submitting an online form 
  * Register to attend an RSM event 
  * Register for one of our email publications 
  * Applying to work for an RSM group entity 

The information required is necessary to enable RSM UK or one of its related entities to deal with your enquiry, but additional information may be requested to help us to provide the most appropriate response. If such additional information is requested, it is highlighted and its provision is voluntary.

Sensitive information is not sought through the Site or Emails except where legally required as part of the recruitment process. Sensitive information includes data relating to: race or ethnic origin; political opinions; religious or other similar beliefs; trade union membership; physical or mental health; sexual life or criminal record. Where you do provide sensitive information this will be accepted as explicit consent to RSM UK or one of its related entities to use that information in connection with the purpose for which it has been provided.

**Email communications**

If you have registered to receive emails from RSM UK you have the option to opt out or to change your email preferences. This option can be found in the footer of the email. 

### Use of information

Information is used only for the specific purpose for which it was provided except where you explicitly select to receive other information from RSM UK or one of its related entities.

You can opt out of receiving information from RSM UK or one of its related entities or request that your personal details are deleted from our systems at any time by emailing us here: [info@rsmuk.com](mailto:info@rsmuk.com).

### Accuracy of information

RSM UK assumes responsibility for keeping an accurate record of personal data once you have submitted the information, but not for confirming the on-going accuracy of your personal information. If you advise RSM UK that your personal data is no longer accurate, it will be amended (where practical).

### Provision of information to third parties

Information is normally only provided to a third party if it is required to deal with your enquiry, but there may be other circumstances where RSM UK is required to provide information as a result of legal process.

RSM UK does not undertake marketing activities for third parties, nor does it provide information to third parties for their own marketing purposes.

### Retention of information

Information is kept for as long as is necessary to fulfil your request or deal with your job application.

Where you have consented to additional information being provided by RSM UK or one of its related entities your details will be retained for a reasonable period of time.

### Security of information

The data controller collecting the information described in this statement is RSM UK. Unless you instruct us otherwise, information you provide will be used by the UK group of companies and LLPs trading as RSM and controlled (directly or indirectly) by RSM UK Holdings Limited (“ **RSM group entities** ”). Personal data collected by RSM UK will not be transferred to other members of the RSM network.

Generally accepted standards of technology and operational security have been implemented to protect personal information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. All personnel of RSM group entities are required to keep personal information confidential and only authorised persons have access to such information.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement please [email us](mailto:info@rsmuk.com)[.](mailto:info@rsmuk.com)
